[thunder rumbles]
[man] There was a time when the world
was plunging into darkness and chaos.
A time of witchcraft and sorcery.
A time when no one stood against evil.
[cannons firing]
[men shouting indistinctly]
[sailor] Fire!
[groaning and shouting]
Come on!
[man screaming]
Yes?
[shouting continues]
[man speaks in Arabic]
[continues in Arabic]
[groaning, gasping]
Where is the throne room?
Shh. Now...
[speaking Arabic]
- No?
- [man whimpering]
[speaking Arabic]
[speaks Arabic]
Good lad. Good lad.
Now...
...let not one of these
putrid heathens live.
[man whimpers]
[speaks Arabic]
[gunshot echoing]
- There's something in here with us.
- No treasure is worth this.
Silence, you dogs.
[indistinct whispers]
[hissing]
[grunting]
Ah!
Hold steady!
Captain, there's
devilry here, I knew it.
I said, "hold steady."
I am the only devil here!
[rumbling]
Now...
...follow me!
Here it is, boys!
I've found it.
[chuckles]
[men screaming]
Malthus!
[men screaming, groaning]
[silence]
[faint whispering]
[faint hissing]
[crackling]
[screeching]
[footsteps]
[demonic voice] Solomon.
[high-pitched screams]
[screams and whispers]
[demonic voice] Killer.
[low growl]
[demonic voice] Solomon.
What... are you?
[roaring]
Ah!
I am the Devil's Reaper.
[demonic voice] Reaper...
I am here to claim you, Solomon Kane.
[demonic voice] Solomon...
Your deal is done.
What deal? I made no deal.
There was a deal,
and your soul is the price.
Your life of murder
and greed is over.
You cannot take my soul.
- Bow your head before me.
- Ah!
The Devil will have his due.
No!
You can tell your master
that I am not yet ready for hell.
The Lord protects me.
Fool! He has abandoned you.
On your knees.
Never! You'll never take my soul!
[demonic voice] Take his soul.
Never!
[Devil's Reaper] You cannot escape us.
Your soul is damned!
Solomon Kane (2009)
[bell tolling]
[monks chanting]
[knocking]
Solomon?
[Solomon] Who's the novice?
[older monk] This is Brother Thomas.
He joined us only a few days ago.
Those marks, do they...
...really protect you from Satan?
Mind what you name
in this holy place.
I would like to speak
with Solomon alone.
[man] Once again, we heard
your cries at matins.
[Solomon] My dreams.
My dreams do haunt me still.
You would do well to listen
to what your dreams tell you.
I do.
My dreams tell me
only that I am damned.
[man] God protects His own.
I am not one of His own...
...am I?
My enemies are...
...are ever watchful of me.
But this place...
...this place and these prayers,
symbols.
They are all that
hide me from its gaze.
Solomon...
...these months you've been here,
I've felt a shadow growing over us.
[Solomon] Aye. These are dark times.
I prayed for guidance,
and I was answered.
Solomon, you must leave us.
Why? I...
I live here in solitude.
I do no harm.
I've renounced my evil ways,
my power.
I'm learning...
learning to be a man of peace.
I know you are, but your
future is not here with us.
How could you do this to me?
I have given all my wealth
to the Church.
We're grateful for your generosity,
of course,
- but you must understand...
- No. Father. Father!
Do not... do not make me beg.
This place is a...
is a sanctuary to me.
- Where would you have me go?
- You must go home.
Home?
You're of noble birth.
You have lands in the west.
You must return to your inheritance.
- No.
- Solomon.
No! I cannot return home.
Nor can you remain.
I was told in my dreams
he was to be sent from here.
I listen to what I'm told.
Does Kane know his purpose?
Every man must discover
his own destiny.
Kane must find his purpose.
There are many paths to redemption.
Not all of them peaceful.
[woman crying]
[crow cawing]
Pilgrim!
- Offer you a ride?
- Thanks, friend, but no.
Well, the road ahead should
not be traveled alone.
Again, I'll thank you for your offer.
I'll be walking.
As you wish. God be with you.
And with you too, sir. Ma'am.
[exclaims]
[footsteps]
- [man 1] He'll hear us.
- [man 2] I don't care.
Let him hear me.
Move and you die. [whistles]
[laughter]
I don't want any trouble.
Well, that's too bad.
- Because you've already got it!
- [grunts]
Let's have a look.
- Nothing worth stealing.
- Nothing? You got nothing?
- Are you a priest?
- Just take what you want.
Oh, don't you worry, pilgrim, we will.
- [laughs]
- Hey, hey, hey.
- Stay still.
- Look at this.
These are magical symbols.
I say he's a sorcerer.
What shall we do with you, eh?
Shall we burn you as a witch?
Burn him! Burn him!
- [growls]
- Oh! Oh...
There's murder in your eyes, traveler.
- Would you kill me? Eh?
- [laughter]
Huh? Would you?
- No.
- What?
[laughter]
You won't kill the man
who steals from you?
[grunts]
I will not fight another man.
I have renounced violence.
Well, that's a shame,
because we haven't.
[man] You will do as I say, Solomon.
Don't forget your place.
You are the second son only.
Marcus is my heir.
He will be master of these lands on my
death. You...
But, Father, Marcus is
a brute and a bully!
You will take holy orders and
join the Church as I command.
But I do not want to be a priest.
What you want is of no importance.
Father Simnal is here
to take you to the abbey.
I won't go.
If you defy me,
you will have nothing.
I will cut you off.
You will be a landless vagrant.
Is that what you want?
Walk out now and
you may never return.
Do not defy me!
- [screeches]
- Oh! [gasping]
[girl] Be calm.
Be calm, sir.
Be calm, you are safe.
He's awake. Father!
Father, that man, he's awake.
Here. Take a drink
of water if you can.
Careful. Careful.
- Meredith.
- His fever has broken, Father.
[man] Thank the Lord, sir.
You will be well.
My name is Crowthorn.
William Crowthorn.
My daughter Meredith
has been tending you.
The good Lord must be
watching over you, sir.
He guided us to your rescue.
Edward, pull over.
We'll find a place
to make camp for the night.
Shall I put these down here, Mother?
[woman] Yes, thank you, Meredith.
Step lively, Meredith.
Samuel.
- Water the horses.
- Why me?
Your older brother has given
you a task. See you set to it.
Master Kane.
You should be resting.
I can hardly repay
your hospitality with...
...with idleness, ma'am.
Give me a few moments to clean up.
I'll come and help you as I can.
You've regained
your appetite, Master Kane.
It's a... it's a fine meal,
Mistress Crowthorn.
[William] My Katherine
can make anything taste good.
- Leather boots and nettles last Sunday.
- [Katherine] It certainly was not!
- Tasted like it.
- [all chuckle]
[Katherine] William tells us
you were captain of a ship.
Yeah. That I was.
- Did you fight the Spanish?
- I did.
[Samuel] Who else?
Seem to have fought
everyone at some time.
I've had many masters.
Once voyaged with Admiral Drake.
Admiral Drake!
That did not end well.
[chuckles]
[Meredith] Must have been so exciting.
Seeing the world
and learning new things.
Why do you think a life of violence
and bloodshed is so admirable, Meredith?
[Meredith] That's not
what I meant and you know it.
Edward, why do you always argue
with everything I say?
- Because you need to learn what to...
- I fought in the Queen's Army once.
- Yeah?
- Before I found my faith.
Now, taking another man's life,
that's...
...that's not an easy thing
to do, don't you agree?
I must confess, Mr. Crowthorn...
...I was never more at home
than I was in battle.
Killing came easily to me.
[Solomon's father] If you defy me,
you will have nothing.
Walk out now
and you may never return.
Do not defy me! [echoing]
- [woman screaming]
- [Marcus shouting]
- Stop!
- Please!
- Please, help me! No!
- Shut up!
Stop!
Marcus, what are you doing?
Solomon, I thought
you'd run away already.
Fleeing the life of a holy man.
- Solomon, he tried to...
- Quiet!
- I gave you no leave to speak!
- Sarah, run!
This is not your concern,
little brother.
Since you're going away,
here's something to remember me by.
- Ah!
- Come here and look at this!
I am the first-born! I am the heir!
All this will be mine
and you'll have nothing!
Take your bags and leave this land!
Ah!
- [screams]
- Marcus!
Marcus!
- Friend. Friend.
- [sighs]
Please, sit down. Join me.
Thank you.
How are you feeling?
Aches, bruises. Nothing.
Your daughter has a healer's gift.
She does indeed.
Just like her mother.
Two most beautiful women
in this world, Master Kane.
My family is all
and everything to me.
You are blessed.
- Do you have kin?
- No. I had a brother.
But that was a lifetime ago now.
We've lost loved ones.
To plague, persecution and bigotry.
Well, Edward, now, he...
had a wife and child once.
But the Lord saw fit to embrace them.
So... now you sail
for the New World, huh?
Yes, indeed, we do.
Sometimes...
we all need to start again.
You might consider joining us.
Well, that's a...
that's a kind offer, William.
Thank you. Very kind.
I should be honest with you.
You should know the kind of man
you're thinking about taking in.
I've done bad things.
Terrible things.
Cruel things.
I am a...
No, I was...
...was an evil...
...evil man.
But the Lord speaks of
redemption and forgiveness.
No. My soul is damned.
Satan's creatures will take me
should I stray
from the path of peace.
Then do not stray...
...Master Kane.
Do not stray.
Captain Kane?
Yes, miss?
I made these clothes... for you.
Your others are a little...
A little what, miss?
A little...
...worn.
[chuckles]
Thank you, miss.
Thank you.
Now there stands a fine figure of a man.
Don't you think, William?
Well, it's better than those rags
you were wearing, and that's a fact.
I'm glad I meet with
your approval, ma'am.
Finally, you're respectable.
Been a long time since
anybody said that about me.
Thank you.
[Samuel] Are you going to
come to America with us?
[Solomon] I'm not so sure, Samuel.
- Why?
- Well...
You and your family
are beginning a new life.
Whereas I need
to undo an old one.
- Those men who hurt you...
- Mm-hm?
You could have killed them
if you wanted, couldn't you?
There was a time when I...
...would have ripped
their still-beating hearts
from their chests.
Would you fight me?
I will if you continue
with your infernal questioning.
Fight me.
I have no reason to fight you,
young man.
- [Meredith] Samuel, stop it!
- Now you have a reason!
To save this beautiful
maiden from me.
[William] Samuel,
don't scare the horses.
Solomon, save me! Help!
- Come, sir.
- [grunting]
Come on.
- Ah!
- [chuckles]
Samuel, get back to the cart. Go on.
[fire crackling]
- Who could have done this?
- The Devil.
The Devil was here.
No, there was no Devil.
There was a witch burning here.
The creature must have broken free.
...to whom vengeance
belongeth, show thyself.
- Lift up thyself...
- We should leave.
[Edward] We can't just leave
these people for carrion.
[William speaking indistinctly]
[screams]
[William] Keep her well stoked, Edward.
We got to keep the shadows
at bay tonight.
Child, can you tell us
what happened?
Oh, let the poor girl be, William.
[girl] They tried to burn a witch.
People came to watch her die, but...
...the flames, they didn't hurt her.
She just laughed and... she said...
She said...
that all the Devil's children
were free to walk the earth now.
And then...
- ...she killed them all.
- Oh.
She burnt out their eyes
because they came to watch.
- [Edward] We should pray.
- I'm tired.
Just a moment more.
- For our prayers.
- I don't want to pray.
[Meredith] It's all right,
it's all right.
I'm so tired. Please?
Of course you are. You poor thing.
Let's find a place for you to sleep.
Edward, I think the child
should wear your cross tonight.
- For protection.
- Of course.
- Here.
- Thank you.
Here, child.
Wear this tonight.
- It will keep you safe.
- Solomon...
[in demonic voice] It's you we want.
Ah!
- What did you do?
- [Katherine] Meredith.
Here, child.
- [growls]
- Her, this is the witch!
- Get her!
- Solomon!
The Devil is waiting for you, Kane!
[hisses, growling]
[cawing, echoing]
[shouting, screaming]
Bring them.
Get off me!
More recruits for Malachi, my Lord.
Are you ready to serve your Overlord?
It's better than
the alternative, aye, lads?
To serve us you have to join us.
Well...
...just tell us what to do.
[growling]
What's he doing?
[chuckles maniacally]
It's good.
[Samuel] Father, I have the firewood.
Well done, Samuel. Break it up now.
Let me help you with that.
Give it a pull.
- There we are.
- Thank you.
Here... let me see.
- Does that hurt?
- No. I can't feel anything.
Why did that... creature mark me?
I don't know.
Evil has its own reasons.
Are we safe?
Don't you worry.
There is no evil in you, Meredith.
Trust me.
I trust you.
[William] Come along
with that wood, Samuel.
Bigger than that now, please.
Bigger pieces. We want hot soup.
[Solomon] William.
You might want to set
a smaller fire tonight.
Don't want to attract
any unwanted attention.
[horse whinnies]
- Solomon!
- What's the matter?
- I heard something.
- Where?
Over there. Beyond those trees.
Wait here.
[screaming, shouting]
Samuel. Samuel, keep down!
Shh.
Keep down, keep quiet!
Who are they?
Solomon, what are they?
I want you to go
back to your father.
Tell him to move out immediately.
Go!
- [screaming, shouting]
- [William] Leave her!
Meredith!
Mother!
- [grunts]
- Solomon! Solomon!
Samuel!
[horse whinnies]
Solomon!
This is the one.
No! Stop! Stop!
Solomon! Help us!
- No!
- Samuel!
- No, leave him be.
- [screaming]
Leave him be. Don't you hurt him.
- I am unarmed.
- [sobbing]
Solomon, help him!
- Solomon, kill them!
- Silence, Samuel!
- Kill them all!
- Listen to him, Samuel. Listen.
Don't struggle, lad.
If you don't struggle, he'll let you go.
Won't you?
Kill him. You know you can.
Just be quiet, Samuel!
You.
Are you their master?
What is it you want?
I'll do anything.
[choking]
Kill me.
Can you?
No, I... I cannot.
I am...
...a man of peace.
Don't you hurt that boy.
This boy...
...this child has more heart
than any of you.
- Help me.
- He is the only man here.
- No! No, listen to me.
- Solomon, stop him!
- No!
- [all shouting]
- Samuel!
My son!
Take the marked one.
Solomon, do something!
Help us!
Kill them! Kill them all!
Solomon, please help us! Please!
What is it you want from me?
What is it?
Is this all I am to you?
Then so be it.
If I kill you...
...I am bound for hell.
It is a price I shall gladly pay.
[screaming]
Go, Meredith!
Leave her!
No! William!
[shouting]
[Katherine] Meredith!
Leave her!
Get off her! Meredith!
Ah!
[straining]
[grunts]
[shouting]
Meredith!
Go, go!
[urging horses]
- Solomon.
- Yeah.
- Get her back.
- Oh, I will.
- I will.
Swear on oath...
...to get her back for me.
These are my last words on earth.
I know God in heaven hears.
If you save our child,
your soul, too, will be saved.
You can redeem yourself, Solomon.
I know this to be true.
Swear it to me.
- Swear.
- I swear.
I swear it, William.
I will find her.
Find her.
Go.
[man groaning]
[growling]
Yah! Go on!
[men shouting]
Get him!
[horse whinnies]
Ah!
- [screaming]
- Help us!
Meredith, are you in there?
Have you seen this girl?
No, no. Look at it, please.
I don't know her, sir. Please...
Where are they taking you?
Have you seen this girl?
I don't know.
There are raiders everywhere.
Please!
No, look at this!
Have you seen this girl?!
Please don't hurt me.
I just want to go home.
Forgive me, child. Forgive me.
Go, go. Go in peace.
Move along.
- Clear out the dead.
- They're no use to Malachi.
Where are you taking us?
What do you want?
Make your peace, child.
There's no way out for us.
Slavery or death.
That's our only way out.
God will not deliver us from this.
We'll find a way out.
Take my hand.
We'll find the strength
to survive this.
Quiet!
[man] Bring her here.
[horse whinnying]
[thunder cracks]
Hyah!
Dear God.
[sobbing]
[bell tolls]
Dear God, I beg you
to listen to me now.
I have failed you.
I cannot find her.
I am lost
and I need your light
to help me find my way.
[grunts]
Forgive me, Father.
Such times we live in.
I wished only for some refuge
and a moment of prayer.
Praise God in His sanctuary.
Praise Him in the firmament
of His power.
I've seen such terrible things.
- So this is your home?
- I need nowhere else.
I have nowhere else.
You come far?
Three days' hard ride
have brought me here.
But where here is I know not.
These are the borderlands
of Somerset and Devonshire.
My home, too.
Sad homecoming for you, then.
Have those raiders been here?
Those black-eyed lapdogs
of Malachi?
Aye.
They passed through here.
Now they hold sway over all the lands
to the west of here.
Then I shall be riding westward.
Then you shall ride
to your death, my son.
- Who is this Malachi?
- A servant of the Devil.
A sorcerer.
No one ever sees him.
He hides away in his castle
and sends forth
that masked warrior
to do his bidding.
His army makes slaves of the weak
and soldiers of the strong.
But God will save the faithful.
[priest] It's here.
It's here, here.
I have read it.
This is the end of days.
You truly believe that?
Every foul thing that
the light of Christ
kept at bay is crawling
up out of the pit
to curse the land.
I think Christ and all his
angels have been asleep,
whilst we are left to suffer.
You mind your blasphemy!
It can only be as God ordains it.
How can it be right,
that this evil
is left to walk the earth
whilst all we have to
protect ourselves is what?
Simple faith?
It is written in the scriptures.
- [creaking]
- Shh!
What was that?
I heard something outside.
No, my son.
There is nothing evil out there.
Evil is already here.
What do you mean?
Come.
See?
"Satan has desired to have them,
that he may sift them as wheat."
[groaning]
My God.
What was I to do?
You should destroy them, man!
I cannot destroy them.
They were men and women once.
People I knew.
Malachi's curse that changed them
is no fault of theirs.
This is my flock. I keep them.
Care for them.
- I feed them.
- Feed them?
With what?
What do you feed them?
- [hisses]
- Flesh!
Ah!
I deliver you unto Satan's creatures
for the destruction of your flesh,
that your spirit may be saved.
May God have mercy on your soul.
[groaning]
[roaring]
[muffled grunting]
[footsteps]
[screams]
[screaming]
[panting]
[groaning]
[screeching]
[panting]
Friend of yours?
I remember this one, lads.
He's not a fighter. Remember?
What are you doing here, Puritan?
So, you've given yourselves
over to this evil, have you?
You should try it.
Malachi will own all this land
here soon enough.
There's no point in you fighting.
The only thing round here is fighting.
But you don't do that, do you?
Well, you know...
...I may just have changed
my mind about that.
[groaning]
Ah!
No! No! What are you doing?!
What are they?!
Now, this girl, your kind took her.
- Have you seen her?
- I don't know her.
Take a long hard look.
This is your last chance
to save your pitiful life.
- Come on!
- All right, I've seen her.
Where?
Where have you seen her?
She's dead.
Dead?
Don't you lie to me.
No!
I wouldn't lie. I want to live!
Don't you lie to me!
I'm not. She's dead! Dead!
She's not dead!
No! [screaming]
[Solomon] For the bag. Leave it all.
[men chattering, laughing]
[man] Thank you, sir.
Are you sure?
It is him. I knew it.
Sir?
Captain Kane?
I'm Henry Telford.
Do you remember me?
Captain Kane?
I was a mate on the Tiercel
when you captained.
My name's Telford.
Do you remember?
- It's not him.
- It is him! It's Kane.
He can lead us, believe me.
Where to, Henry?
Another tavern? Look at him!
My friend here says
you're the greatest
warrior he ever saw.
- I don't believe him.
- [Solomon] You shouldn't.
I know what you can do, captain.
I've seen it!
Those were distant times.
She's dead now.
And I have...
...forfeit my soul.
- He's no use to us. Leave him!
- No!
Captain Kane, we need a leader.
- We have to fight back!
- Then fight back!
She's lost.
And I lost her.
And I... I am to blame.
Let them come and get me.
I care not.
[muffled shouting]
- [screaming]
- [hammering]
[man] Mercy!
Mercy, please!
This is the fate of those
who defy Malachi!
Please have mercy!
There will be no mercy!
[grunts]
This man cannot save you!
He is nothing!
Crucify him!
And burn the town to the ground!
[grunting]
[groaning]
[shouting, hammering fades]
[grunts]
[horse whinnies]
[shouting, screams]
No, no, no!
Solomon! [screams]
Solomon! God help him!
Solomon! Solomon, please!
Solomon!
- Meredith.
- Can you hear me?
- Meredith!
- Solomon!
Meredith!
God, save me!
[screams]
[grunts]
Captain Kane.
[man] ...another 20 at Romney Marsh.
He's getting stronger all the time.
I don't see how we can win.
[Telford] That's why we need Kane.
We need him,
whatever his past sins were.
But one devil for another
seems like folly.
Earth, fire, stone, and water...
Keep your filthy pagan magic
away from me.
It is my pagan magic
that has healed you.
There's more power here
than your Christian God.
You'd do well to remember that.
I have done what you asked.
His body is healed.
- What do you see of our future?
- [scoffs]
Your champion will lead you
into blood and darkness.
Are you ready for that?
[hissing, demonic voices whispering]
What are you doing?
You need to rest.
- I'm leaving.
- Why?
Because it's not over yet.
She's still alive.
You're barely healed.
And we're too few
to fight Malachi's men.
Just wait a little.
I do not ask you to come with me,
nor do I want you to.
Well, you may not
want it, but we will.
This lad has promised us
you will destroy this evil,
and we're here to fight with you.
[men murmuring]
Promised, have you?
That's what you want, isn't it?
To end this?
Then let us help you.
[Telford] Malachi was
a priest and a healer,
but he sold his soul to the Devil
for the power he now possesses.
He enslaves our people
and corrupts the land.
And the masked rider,
he's the iron fist that commands
his army and spreads the poison.
[man] He has no face
beneath his mask.
He can possess you with his touch.
It's true, I've seen it.
If we kill him,
Malachi will be vulnerable.
- Easier said than done, my friend.
- No.
He will fall.
You know where this Malachi is?
That is no secret. Exmouth Castle.
No... No, that cannot be.
There is no doubt.
Do you know it?
My father was lord of Exmouth Castle.
I grew up there.
There's no lord there now.
I did not even know he'd died.
Now, this must end.
All of you... all of you,
gather your weapons!
- We're not ready.
- It's time to take the fight to him.
- Neither is he!
- We're too few.
- Oh, come on!
You have seen me taking
cities with fewer.
[man] But how do we get through
the front gates?
You forget, I was born here.
I have no intention of
going through the front gates.
[Solomon] Come on.
[Solomon] Good God. My home!
- You lived here?
- Uh-huh.
That explains a lot.
[rattling]
- You!
- Welcome home...
...Solomon Kane.
[screaming]
[shouting]
Telford! Get your men inside!
We cannot win this!
Men!
Follow me!
Meredith?
- [woman] Help us!
- Meredith?
Is there a girl in there
called Meredith?
- [woman] Please help us...
- Meredith?
[grunting]
[gurgling]
[prisoners clamoring]
You're free. All of you.
Get out of here.
Thank you.
[man] Let's get away from here.
Come on, old man, you're free.
All right, I'll help you, then.
Let's see if I can
loosen these chains.
[man] Even if you do, I'll stay.
What are you talking about, man? Why?
Because this was my home.
Father?
Solomon?
I thought I had lost you forever.
You were still a boy when...
You will never break them.
They were spun with dark magic
as much as with metal.
How will I free you?
You can't, Solomon, don't try.
My Father, I have carried such...
...such guilt for what I did.
I did not mean for Marcus to fall.
I did not mean for him to die.
He did not die, Solomon.
If he had, this nightmare
would never have begun.
He did not...?
Thank God he is alive.
It was not through God's will
that he survived.
- Well, what do you mean?
- Well...
He was terribly injured by the fall,
but he didn't die.
But nor did he wake.
No surgeons or priests
could help, so...
I brought the sorcerer here.
- You?
- Yeah.
You brought Malachi here?
I offered him everything I had.
Just to bring Marcus
back to me. Everything.
And he succeeded, Solomon.
With his mirrors and magic
he reached into the darkness
and brought Marcus back.
But... he was changed.
And his face,
so damaged by the fall,
he hid behind a mask
and obeyed only the will
of the sorcerer.
No, he cannot be my brother.
That creature is your brother.
Or what remains.
And now Marcus infects
those who follow him.
One thing you must do for me.
Father, just ask and it shall be done.
We both have our sins to answer for.
And I'm ready to answer for mine...
...now.
- No.
- You have to.
Because I brought the sorcerer here.
And as long as I'm alive,
he will remain.
He will never let me die.
[gunshot]
[shouting]
- Kane! Through here!
- Kane, for God's sake, help us!
Is this it? Is this all you have left?
Fletcher, McNess, Hawkstone, maybe.
The rest I don't know.
- [Solomon] Just keep them back.
- Ah!
- You hold steady now.
- This is your folly.
Just a few more moments.
I think I can stop this
with a single blow.
Malachi?
Malachi!
I'm here for you.
Isn't this what you want?
[footsteps]
Come on.
Solomon!
Solomon, no, it's a trap!
Long is the road
that the pilgrim walks
in the name of his devotion.
Yet longer still is the journey
home to the land of his fathers.
I've been waiting for you.
You are unfit to sit
upon my father's chair.
Your father was a child.
A pathetic fool
who made a pact with the Devil.
He betrayed you.
Your soul is damned.
Get up!
Are you still the good, loyal son?
Malachi?!
Malachi!
Malachi, you coward!
Meredith, are you all right?
- You came for me.
- I swore I would.
Solomon, no, it's a trap!
They only marked me
so that you would come.
No, stop!
The Devil wants you.
The Devil can take me soon enough.
- [grunts]
- [screams]
Oh, God, Solomon!
[groaning]
Brother, listen to me.
If you can hear me, Marcus,
you do not have to do this.
[Meredith] No!
Listen to me!
Meredith, run!
Where is your master?
Eh? Where is he?
Where are you, Malachi?
Hiding in the shadows?
Why should I hide from you?
I want you here.
Every step you took led you to here.
Every pain you suffered was
punishment for your sins.
My master will have your soul!
See what the Devil
has sent to claim you.
This beast will not fail
to drag you back to Hell.
Your soul is damned!
Oh, dear God!
[roaring]
Marcus... our father is dead.
You are lord here now!
Malachi has no control over you!
No!
[groans]
Brother, stop! Brother!
- [grunts]
- [screams]
Solomon!
Rest in peace, brother.
It's time. Only your innocent blood
will release him.
- [Meredith screams]
- [slurping]
[spits]
Now you are free!
[roaring]
- [screaming]
- Kill him!
My God. Only you can help me now.
[roaring]
Stop!
Let her go.
[creature growling]
You can have my soul.
Why would you risk everything,
even your soul...
...to save her?
I made a promise.
- I must keep it.
- [shouts]
[grunts]
- [roaring]
- [screaming]
[sobbing quietly]
Solomon.
[both gasp]
Oh, thank God.
It's gone.
Your father told me...
...that if I saved you
my soul will be redeemed.
I have.
And it is.
And the Devil's claim on me is no more.
[footsteps]
The guards have fallen.
[Solomon] Father,
I have kept my promise
and Meredith is returned
to her mother.
The demon is gone.
Banished to the shadows
along with the sorcerer
who had cursed us all.
But evil is not so easily defeated,
and I know I will
have to fight again.
I am a very different man now.
Through all of my travels,
all the things I've seen
and all the things I've done,
I have found my purpose.
There was a time when the world
was plunging into darkness.
A time of witchcraft and sorcery,
when no one stood against evil.
That time...
...is over.
[grunts and groans throughout]